<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bartosz Zieliński</title>
    <link>https://bartoszpzielinski.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bartosz Zieliński</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 09:59:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bartoszpzielinski.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Threads in Python</title>
      <link>https://bartoszpzielinski.github.io/posts/python-threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 09:59:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bartoszpzielinski.github.io/posts/python-threads/</guid>
      <description>Module threading in Python3 contains functions and objects supporting creation, usage and synchronization of threads. Importantly, this module is portable: scripts using threading should work the same way under Linux, Windows, Mac, and other operating systems.
One limitation of threading module (at least in the CPython implementation) is a global interpreter lock which must be acquired by any thread executing Python interpreter. This effectively makes it impossible for pure Python threads within the same process to execute concurrently on multiple processor cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate Data Streams</title>
      <link>https://bartoszpzielinski.github.io/posts/alternative-data-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 09:18:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bartoszpzielinski.github.io/posts/alternative-data-streams/</guid>
      <description>Hidden data in NTFS Both files and folders in NTFS file system can have additional “forks” of data called alternate data streams (ADS-es in short). If this reminds you of forks on Mac then this is no coincidence: this feature was added to Windows NT explicitly as a support for compatibility with Mac&amp;rsquo;s HFS. In general, the ability to add additional named attachments to any file of folder is a wonderful idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
